It was less than a year after September 11,
بعد أقل من سنة من أحداث 11 سبتمبر،
and I was at the Chicago Tribune
كنت في صحيفة شيكاغو تريبيون
writing about shootings and murders,
أكتب عن إطلاق النار والجرائم،
and it was leaving me feeling
وقد جعلتني أشعر
pretty dark and depressed.
بالسوداوية والإكتئاب.
I had done some activism in college,
قمت بعمل بعض الأنشطة في الجامعة،
so I decided to help a local group
لذا قررت مساعدة مجموعة محلية
hang door knockers against animal testing.
في قرع الأبواب ضد مختبرات الحيوانات.
I thought it would be a safe way
اعتقدت أنها قد تكون طريقة آمنة
to do something positive,
لعمل شئ إيجابي،
but of course I have the absolute worst luck ever,
لكن بالطبع وبما أنني أملك أسوأ حظ على الإطلاق
and we were all arrested.
فقد تم اعتقالنا جميعًا.
Police took this blurry photo of me
ألتقطت الشرطة هذه الصورة المشوشة لي
holding leaflets as evidence.
وأنا أحمل المنشورات كدليل ضدي.
My charges were dismissed,
كل التهم أُسقطت،
but a few weeks later,
لكنها بعدها بأسابيع قليلة،
two FBI agents knocked on my door,
اثنان من عملاء الـ FBI طرقوا بابي،
and they told me that unless I helped them
وأخبروني بأنني إن لم أتعاون معهم
by spying on protest groups,
بالتجسس على المجموعات المتظاهرة،
they would put me on a domestic terrorist list.
سيقومون بوضعي في قائمة الإرهاب المحلي.
I'd love to tell you that I didn't flinch,
أود بشدة أن أخبركم أنني لم أخف،
but I was terrified,
بل ذُعرت،
and when my fear subsided,
وعندما تلاشى خوفي،
I became obsessed with finding out
أصبحت مهووسًا باكتشاف
how this happened,
كيف حدث هذا،
how animal rights and environmental activists
كيف لناشط في حقوق الحيوان والبيئة
who have never injured anyone
الذي لم يؤذي أحد أبدًا
could become the FBI's number one
أن يصبح المهدد رقم واحد في قائمة الـ FBI
domestic terrorism threat.
للإرهاب المحلي.
A few years later, I was invited to testify
بعدها بعدة سنوات، دُعيت لأُدلي بشهادتي
before Congress about my reporting,
أمام الكونغرس عن تقاريري،
and I told lawmakers that, while everybody
أخبرت صُنّاع القرار أنه وبينما الجميع
is talking about going green,
يتحدث على التحول للطاقة النظيفة،
some people are risking their lives
بعض الناس يخاطرون بحياتهم
to defend forests and to stop oil pipelines.
للدفاع عن الغابات وإيقاف أنابيب البترول.
They're physically putting their bodies on the line
يقومون بدنيًا بوضع أجسامهم على الخط
between the whalers' harpoons and the whales.
بين الحيتان وصياديها.
These are everyday people,
هؤلاء هم الناس البسطاء،
like these protesters in Italy
كهؤلاء المتظاهرين في إيطاليا
who spontaneously climbed over
الذين تسلقوا وبعفوية
barbed wire fences to rescue beagles
أسوار ذات أسلاك شائكة لإنقاذ كلب البيقلز
from animal testing.
من الخضوع للإختبار.
And these movements have been incredibly effective
هذه الحركات أصبحت فعالة جدًا
and popular,
ومشهورة،
so in 1985, their opponents made up a new word,
في 1985، ابتكر المعارضون كلمة جديدة،
eco-terrorist,
إرهابيو البيئة،
to shift how we view them.
ليثنونا عن كيفية نظرتنا لهم.
They just made it up.
ابتكروها ببساطة.
Now these companies have backed new laws
هذه الشركات الآن تدعم قوانين جديدة
like the Animal Enterprise Terrorism Act,
مثل ملف إرهاب المشاريع الحيوانية،
which turns activism into terrorism
والذي يعتبر الأنشطة البيئية أعمالًا أرهابية
if it causes a loss of profits.
في حال سببت خسائر في الأرباح.
Now most people never even heard about this law,
معظم الناس الآن لم يسمعوا أبدًا عن هذا القانون،
including members of Congress.
بمن فيهم أعضاء من الكونغرس.
Less than one percent were in the room
أقل من 1% منهم كانوا في القاعة
when it passed the House.
عندما تجاوزت البيت الأبيض.
The rest were outside at a new memorial.
والبقية كانوا في الخارج يقيمون مناسبة تذكارية جديدة.
They were praising Dr. King
كانوا يشيدون بالدكتور كينغ
as his style of activism was branded as terrorism
بينما نمط نشاطه يصنّف كعمل إرهابي
if done in the name of animals or the environment.
لو كان تحتى مسمى الحيوانات أو البيئة.
Supporters say laws like this are needed
الداعمون لهذا القانون يقولون بأنه مطلوب
for the extremists:
للمتطرفين:
the vandals, the arsonists, the radicals.
المخربين، مشعلي الحرائق، والراديكالية.
But right now, companies like TransCanada
لكن الآن، شركات مثل ترانس كندا
are briefing police in presentations like this one
تحيط الشرطة في عروض مرئية مثل هذا
about how to prosecute nonviolent protesters
عن كيفية محاكمة المتظاهرين السلميين
as terrorists.
كإرهابيين.
The FBI's training documents on eco-terrorism
ملفات تدريب الـ FBI بالنسبة للإرهاب البيئي
are not about violence,
لا علاقة لها بالعنف،
they're about public relations.
بل بالعلاقات العامة.
Today, in multiple countries,
اليوم، وفي عدة دول،
corporations are pushing new laws
تدعم الشركات قوانين جديدة
that make it illegal to photograph
تشرّع لاقانونية تصوير
animal cruelty on their farms.
القسوة ضد الحيوان في مزارعهم.
The latest was in Idaho just two weeks ago,
آخرها كان في إيداهو قبل أسبوعين فقط،
and today we released a lawsuit
واليوم أصدرنا دعوة قضائية
challenging it as unconstitutional
نتحدى فيها بأن هذا غير دستوري
as a threat to journalism.
ويعتبر تهديد لعمل الصحافة.
The first of these ag-gag prosecutions,
أولى الملاحقات القضائية لإسكات المتظاهرين،
as they're called,
كما يسمونها،
was a young woman named Amy Meyer,
كانت إمرأة شابة تدعى إيمي ماير،
and Amy saw a sick cow being moved
رأت إيمي بقرة مريضة تُجر
by a bulldozer outside of a slaughterhouse
إلى خارج المسلخ بواسطة بلدوزر
as she was on the public street.
بينما كانت تقف على شارع عام.
And Amy did what any of us would:
وقد قامت إيمي بعمل ما قد يفعله معظمنا:
She filmed it.
قامت بتصويره.
When I found out about her story, I wrote about it,
عندما علمت بقصتها، كتبت عنها،
and within 24 hours, it created such an uproar
وفي خلال 24 ساعة، أحدثت هيجانا لدرجة
that the prosecutors just dropped all the charges.
أن النيابة العامة أسقطت كل التهم.
But apparently, even exposing stuff like that
لكن من الواضح، أن كشف مثل هذه الأشياء
is a threat.
يعتبر تهديدًا.
Through the Freedom of Information Act,
من خلال قانون حرية المعلومات،
I learned that the counter-terrorism unit
علمت أن وحدة مكافحة الإرهاب
has been monitoring my articles
تراقب عمودي الصحفي
and speeches like this one.
وخطاباتي مثل هذا الآن.
They even included this nice little write-up of my book.
حتى أنهم أضافوا هذه المقولة اللطيفة من كتابي.
They described it as "compelling and well-written."
ووصفوها بأنها "مُقنعة ومكتوبة بعناية."
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Blurb on the next book, right?
تعتبر دعاية لكتابي القادم، أليس كذلك؟
The point of all of this is to make us afraid,
الهدف من وراء هذا كله هو إخافتنا،
but as a journalist, I have an unwavering faith
لكن كصحفي، لدي إيمان مطلق
in the power of education.
في قوة التعليم.
Our best weapon is sunlight.
سلاحنا الأفضل هو ضوء الشمس.
Dostoevsky wrote that the whole work of man
كتب ديستوفيسكي أن مهمة الإنسان المطلقة
is to prove he's a man and not a piano key.
هي إثبات أنه بشر وليس مفتاح بيانو.
Over and over throughout history,
دائمًا وأبدًا على مر التاريخ،
people in power have used fear
استخدم أصحاب السلطة الخوف
to silence the truth and to silence dissent.
لإسكات الحقيقة ولإسكات المعارضة.
It's time we strike a new note.
حان الوقت لعزف لحن جديد.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)